Finding Aid for United Press International State Capitol Bureau informational files, 1958-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
United Press International State Capitol Bureau informational files
1958-1990
1981-1989
United Press International. State Capitol Bureau.
9566 Bb 2
Lansing, Michigan bureau of United Press International. Collected informational files relating to news and events in the state of Michigan. The files consist mainly of UPI wire reports, press releases, correspondence, and clippings. The files also include collected biographical information about, and distributed press releases from, Michigan legislators.
3 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This record group (Donor No. 8392 ) was donated by the State Capitol Bureau and came through Rick Pluta in August 1995.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The UPI State Capitol Bureau reports on news and events unfolding in the state of Michigan. The bureau, located in Lansing, maintains informational files to be used by staff members in the preparation of news stories. The files, consisting of a culling together of previously released information, provide overviews, often in the form of day-by-day reports, of unfolding or formerly unfolding events. These informational files include United Press International (UPI) wire reports, press releases, correspondence, clippings, and other materials.
The UPI State Capitol Bureau informational files collection is broken up into two series: Background Files, and Michigan Politician Files. Each series has been retained in its original order with original folder headings.
Subjects:
United Press International. State Capitol Bureau.; Abortion--Michigan.; Michigan. Legislature.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Michigan--Politics and government--1971-1980.; Michigan--Politics and government--1981-1990.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
- Background Files, 1968-1990
  Background Files (1968-1990; 2.5 linear ft.) consist of information maintained to give UPI employees quick references to certain subjects, events, and individuals. The files consist primarily of AP wire reports and press releases issued by individuals and companies.
  - Abortion
    - Issues, 1972-1989 (Box 1)
    - Parental Consent, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Tax Funded, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Welborn Bills, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Agriculture, 1985 (Box 1)
  - AIDS, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Air Pollution and Acid Rain, 1982-1987 (Box 1)
  - Banks, 1968-1987 (Box 1)
  - Business Taxes and Single Business Tax (SBT), 1975-1988 (Box 1)
  - Blacks, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  - Blue Cross and Blue Shield of Michigan, 1980-1988 (Box 1)
  - Budgets and Budget Stabilization, 1976-1989 (Box 1)
  - Business, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  - Campaign Finances, 1976-1990 (Box 1)
  - Children, Abuse Laws and Care Cases, 1982-1988 (Box 1)
  - Church and School, 1984-1987 (Box 1)
  - Civil Rights, 1977-1987 (Box 1)
  - Civil Service, Department of, 1981-1986 (Box 1)
  - Colleges and Universities, 1981-1987 (Box 1)
  - Compensation for Workers, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Consumers Power Company, Mid, 1981-1989 (Box 2)
  - Crime, 1981-1989 (Box 2)
  - Death Penalty, 1969-1990 (Box 2)
  - Department of Natural Resources (DNR), 1983-1987 (Box 2)
  - Detroit Riots, undated (Box 2)
  - Detroit Riots II, undated (Box 2)
  - Dioxin, 1983-1987 (Box 2)
  - Drugs, 1981-1989 (Box 2)
  - Education, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Economic Development, 1983-1987 (Box 2)
  - Environment, 1987-1989 (Box 2)
  - Great Lakes, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
  - Income Tax, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Insurance, 1971-1990 (Box 2)
  - Legislature, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
  - Licensing and Regulation, 1975-1985 (Box 2)
  - Lottery, 1981-1988 (Box 3)
  - Mackinac Bridge, 1958-1987 (Box 3)
  - Pigeon River, 1975-1980 (Box 3)
  - Plane Crash, Northwest 255, 8/16/1987; 1987 (Box 3)
  - Prisons, 1981-1987; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Radioactive Waste, 1987-1989 (Box 3)
  - Toxics and Hazardous Wastes, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - Welfare, 1984-1987 (Box 3)
- Michigan Politician Files, 1986-1989
  Michigan Politician Files (1986-1989; .5 linear ft.) consist of biographical information produced by UPI and others about Michigan State Senators and State Representatives. The series also contains press releases issued by Michigan State Senators and State Representatives.
  - Arthurhultz, Phil, undated (Box 3)
  - Barcia, James, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Binsfeld, Connie, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Basil, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Carl, Doug, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Cherry, John Jr., 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Conroy, Joe, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Cropsey, Harmon, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Cruce, Doug, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - DeGrow, Dan, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Dillingham, Frederick, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - DiNello, Gilbert, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Ehlers, Vernon, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Engler, John, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Faust, William, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Faxon, Jack, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Fessler, Richard, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Fredricks, Ed, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Gast, Harry, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Geake, R. Robert, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Hart, George, undated (Box 3)
  - Hart, Jerome, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Holmes, David S., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Irwin, Mitch, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Kelly, John, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Miller, Art, undated (Box 3)
  - Nichols, Rudy, 1985-1988 (Box 3)
  - O'Brien, Michael, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Pollack, Lana, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Posthumus, Dick, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - Schwarz, John, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Sederburg, William, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Shinkle, Norman, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Smith, Nick, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - Smith, Virgil Jr., 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Vaughn, Jackie, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Welborn, Jack, 1987-1988 (Box 3)